Natnael Kiflu

Python Developer

+251924325817

@ natty7kt@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/natnael-kiflu

AAAAA

SUMMARY

Solutions-oriented Python software developer with 4+ years of experience in back-end development and automation script motivated to stay on task, meet aggressive timelines, and accomplish goals. Driven to learn quickly, advance computer proficiency, and train in software development operations. Flexible and hardworking team player focused on boosting productivity and performance with conscientious and detailed-oriented approaches

EXPERIENCE

Python Developer

Soft-Valley

2019 - 2020 Addis Ababa

Soft-valley Technology Group is one of the leading Information Technology Solution Companies in Ethiopia, with a strong talented team that provides extensive range of products and services.

- · Performed on product catalogue module
- · Developed CRM using Django as backend developer
- · Established a team of 3 members covering the overall software development lifecycle
- Delivering projects with 1-2 days turn around time or even within

Python Developer

Nano Computing ICT solutions

2020 - 2021 Addis Ababa, Bole

Nano computing & ICT Solution Specializes in providing solutions in almost all verticals of IT.

- · Developed Inventory management system for local use
- Worked as tech lead for a team of 5
- · Developed shell scripting and Python programs to automate the data flow on day-to-day tasks
- · Developed Different Business website for the clients

CERTIFICATION



ICPC | ACPC | EtCPC

First to solve problem A The 2020 Ethiopian Collegiate Programming Contest



ICPC | ACPC | EtCPC

First to solve problem C

The 2020 Ethiopian Collegiate Programming Contest



Zindi

Natnael Kiflu has participated in the

- Road Segment identification
- UmojaHack Africa 2022: African Snake Antivenom Binding Challenge (ADVANCED)

SKILLS

Programming

Python PHP Diango **FastAPI** Django REST Framework **HTML** CSS JS. **SQL**

Databases & Servers

Postgresql Django ORM MongoDB **MySQL Apache** Hadoop Spark

Development

GIT VS code Jupyter notebook

EXPERIENCE

Junior Python Developer

MoR

🛗 2021 - Ongoing 👂 Addis Ababa

MOR will contribute to economic development and social welfare by developing a modern Tax and Customs Administration that employs professional and highly skilled staff who promote voluntary compliance amongst individuals and businesses, and take swift action against those who do not comply.

- Visualized over 6 datasets with Matplotlib and other python libraries
- Involved in processing the streaming data as well as batch data using Apache Spark
- Developed data quality portal using Python scripting, increasing data quality by 30%
- Communicated and coordinated with the project manager and coworkers

to resolve 10+ build breaks a month

STRENGTHS



Time management

Prioritizes essential tasks so they are not rushed. Sets deadlines that ensure reaching milestones on time.



Adaptability

I remember that change is not personal and is inevitable. I break my projects into multiple parts so that if something goes wrong, I can quickly fix it.



Accountability

I take ownership of my mistakes. By doing that I learn what I did wrong so that it does not happen again.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Head of Development division at CSEC-

Computer Science and Engineering Club (CSEC-ASTU)

2022 - Ongoing

Software Development

- lead the software development team and set the team's strategy
- · Project scoping, planning, and management
- · Talent recruitment and mentoring
- · Problem solving, Communication

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science and Engineering

Adama Science and Technology University